Henk van der Schuur Curriculum Vitæ

Personal Details

H.W. van der Schuur hwschuur@gmail.com 답 linkedin.com/in/hwschuur 답 +31 6 51 26 32 40 답



About Me

I bring clarity to complexity by aligning people, purpose, and technology. I strive for excellence, grounded in integrity and transparency. I believe that honest leadership and human connection are what make real progress possible.

Areas of expertise IT Strategy, Business Development, Product Management

Employment

Schuberg Philis

Customer Director, 2017-present

- I work with diverse expert teams for customers in vital industries, taking full end-to-end and P&L responsibility. We root out the business challenges behind the technology questions to deliver high-quality, tailored, impactful solutions that meet the highest standards of security, reliability, and performance.
- · Member of the Public, Utility, and Retail (PUR) leadership team
- · Member of the COM Council

AFAS Software

Platform Manager, 2015-2017

- Designed and architected the successor of the successful AFAS Profit product stack: AFAS NEXT (now AFAS SB), a fully generated, cloud-based ERP suite tailored to customer organizations through ontological models
- Founded the AMUSE research initiative: a collaboration between academic partners (Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, Utrecht University) and industry partners (AFAS Software).

Product Manager, 2011-2015

- End-to-end responsible for the roadmap, design, build, and delivery of the AFAS Profit ERP software suite
- Shipped more than 150 projects across Profit Finance, CRM, Projects, Order Management, and Subscriptions to more than 10,000 customers in retail, education, healthcare, construction, wholesale and other industries

Utrecht University

PhD Researcher, 2008-2011

- Conducted a PhD research directed at revealing the potential of software feedback, i.e., knowledge of in-the-field software operation, within Dutch independent software vendors. Created Nuntia, a binary instrumentation and recompilation tool. Successfully defended my PhD thesis after 3,5 years of research
- Led an industry workgroup with software vendors from the Netherlands, bridging academics and industry to gain early feedback and share research results

Stabiplan (now Trimble)

Senior Software Engineer, 2008–2011

DEVENTIT

Junior Software Engineer, 2003-2008

Education

- · PhD in Information Science, Utrecht University, 2011
- · Master in Information Science (Business Informatics research master), Utrecht University, 2008
- · Bachelor in Computer Science (Business Studies minor), Utrecht University, 2006
- · VWO (Natuur & Techniek; Informatica, Economie 1), Griftland College, 2003

Selected Publications and Talks

Popular

- Adding Soul to the System: Our Strive for DevOps Significance @ DevOpsDays Amsterdam, 2024. Duo talk.
- Be More than a Product Owner—Start Product Thinking @ Medium, 2023. Story.
- Manifesto for a Product Mindset in Agile Development @ Tweakers Developers Summit, 2022. Conference talk.
- BizDevOps: Bridging the Dominant Divide between Business and IT (2) DevOpsDays Amsterdam, 2020. Keynote talk.
- Bye Bye Time & Materials—Entering the Era of Agile, Value-based Agreements (2) Agile Amsterdam, 2019. Conference talk.
- Pakketleveranciers laks—Softwaremakers kijken te weinig naar praktijksituatie bij klanten. 2 Automatisering Gids, 19, 2011. Featured cover article.

Academic

- H. van der Schuur, E. van de Ven, R. de Jong, D. Schunselaar, H.A. Reijers, M. Overeem, M. de Graaf, S. Jansen and S. Brinkkemper. **NEXT: Generating Tailored ERP Cloud Applications from Ontological Enterprise Models** In PoEM'17: Proceedings of the 10th IFIP WG 8.1. Working Conference on the Practice of Enterprise Modeling. Springer, 2017, pp. 283–298.
- H. van der Schuur. **Process Improvement through Software Operation Knowledge—If the SOK Fits, Wear It!** \(\text{\textit{Z}} \) PhD dissertation. Utrecht University, 2011.
- H. van der Schuur, S. Jansen and S. Brinkkemper. **Reducing Maintenance Effort through Software Operation Knowledge: An Eclectic Empirical Evaluation** 1. In CSMR'11: Proceedings of the 15th European Conference on Software Maintenance and Reengineering. IEEE Computer Society, 2011, pages 201–210.

Selected Guest Lectures

- · Advanced Program Zorgmanagement: Strategie & Digitale Transformatie. Nyenrode Business Universiteit, 2023–2024.
- · Innovation in Practice: Data & Al. Nyenrode Business Universiteit, 2023–2024.
- · Software Production and Software Product Management. Utrecht University, 2014–2019.

Licenses and Certifications

- · Nyenrode Masterclass Bedrijfskunde voor niet-bedrijfskundigen
- · Tuff Leadership Training (Step 1, Step 2)
- · AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner; Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals AZ-900
- Passenger car (B); heavy motorcycle (AZ); passenger car with trailer (BE)
- · PADI Advanced Open Water Diver